tree waiting it's really hot I think I
might take my shirt off that's
appropriate you get banned from twitch
for that can't girls take their shirt
off with which saddle out but we're
gonna do it we're gonna do it cuz I was
out all day
I'm not gonna wear a shirt for this
stream I don't know what that means I
don't know what that means but that's
what's gonna happen all right wait so
I'm when you're in the chat is anybody
here
I don't know this really isn't great oh
here we go yeah flex no no this is I
mean you know I'm into handsome men as
much as the next guy but I'm gonna talk
about that so first we're gonna go over
the drinks we have here we have a 100
plus I heard from my date that this is
an isotonic this I I went on a date no I
know bang no bang um I went on a date
with an advertisement like this girl was
we went okay so first off we didn't meet
last night because of drama not my drama
and I met her this morning
for coffee and we walked around the mall
this girl was an ad like like I don't
there's gotta be something yo you guys
ever see ads on the internet and you
wonder who clicks the ads like I just
don't know who clicks the ads I found
them alright no I don't talk about that
stuff that stuff that stuff's not what
the girls are interested in I talk about
traveling talk about other women girls
like that who date's an ad that's what
I'm
all right so that's that um what else do
I talk about talk about high school
that's just cuz I'm emo alright so today
we're drinking 100 plus an isotonic
drink and of course amazingly available
in this country same cream cheese I was
drinking in Japan they're actually kind
of better I only export like the
high-end stuff which is crazy to think
Japan but oh right there in geohawk
configuration on github I also committed
twitch cgw to github so if you guys want
to follow along at home you now can so
first thing I'm gonna do is gonna look
up suffix trees this is cuz this is like
a common thing
hundred-plus why does where stream
shirtless tonight is this not cool this
Malaysia man this is this fun is chilly
I don't worry hundred-plus what did I
say good morning it's not sleepy time
it's one 7:30 look at my computer right
up here all right
oh it's not 100 plus it's just hundred
plus I say
okay so I mean so I looked over this
paper a bit more this morning it turns
out that this paper describes things
that are incredibly simple in the most
complicated way you can believe like
this denotes the probability right but
all this stuff says is that it's between
0 & 1
and it's a real number like everybody
knows that about it probabilities you
don't have to say that right and then
like this whole thing has an integral in
it and you're like what the fuck's an
integral I don't know but then you
realize that it's actually just this so
when you realize it's just this you
realize that we have the wrong numbers
here so yesterday I had these set at 1 &
2 and you'll see that with 1 & 2
let's just see that with 1 & 2 I get 50
200 bytes of entropy but then if I use
that cough geek romanov estimator it
goes down to 5,000 so if you guys
remember get a gzip is down at 37 angry
yeah I mean I don't think it's that like
I really don't think these people wrote
it to be like oh I'm smart I think
that's just like how they think about
things
we're just sensible I guess I don't know
I'm just kind of not used to it
yeah mathematical rigor no one should be
better at that well how do you learn to
be mathematically rigorous guys okay so
when you read this whole thing um you
realize that it's memory less and all
memory lists is just doesn't uh means it
doesn't even depend in the past yeah
what else piss me off about this the
things start from one things start from
one I think MATLAB does that too and
that's why these people do that okay can
be defined with the source Melanie's
memory a finite variable or by our
market model is one such mom this can be
equivalently described by a binary
prediction suffix tree so I've read this
page I've never actually written the
suffix tree but I've definitely read
this Wikipedia and seen this banana
example multiple times and convinced
myself that I understood it but that's
always questionable I probably copy and
paste the code for suffix trees for the
longest common substring problem in
composition programming
a structure which is a binary tree and a
set of real valued parameters within 0
and 1 with one parameter for each leaf
node of the PST
sure I can crush me because I guess I
want to live in the club right
we all know that mm-hmm okay a suffix
set is a collection of binary strings s
is said to be proper if no string and
ass it's a suffix of any other string
mean s this is complete if every the
does that word mean semi infinite
talk too much it's just semi infinite oh
um I'm gonna look that up
what's a semi infinite mean however I'm
going to be semi infant wow it's a real
thing abandoned in one direction on
bamboo another okay again like fine
there's a word for that it's called
infinite
you know a force like in the word again
but yeah like we're also gonna we're
gonna read the chat a little bit less
again because we're being more serious
in these I understand it may not appear
that way considering out all of a shirt
on but that's just cuz hot here silly
and I'm in this room so I'm not my
apartment anymore which is another
tragedy but that was just poor planning
on my part 100-plus isotonic drink it's
for people with an active lifestyle yeah
most people are there me ads and chat I
have the AC on don't worry don't worry
the AC is definitely on the problem is
it's one of those rooms that has the
door thingy and they only give you one
key you know cuz they know what you want
to do is the door thingy that switches
the power so I just got home from a long
walk I saw monkeys yo yo guys know I'll
shop I showed you the monkeys I'll have
to close chat seven can't show you the
monkeys but well like it's not like I
saw monkeys in cage they were just like
monkeys chillin by the street i sat
there for a bit like we talked no you
can't put literally any card that's only
the cheap ones the good ones have
actually gotten better and have attached
a string oh and leave it and leave it
while I'm gone that that would work I
think they're macaque yeah they were
little um I wasn't afraid of him
okay
like
maybe we should read a little bit more
about the suffix trees but I do think I
know how to write this
I just have a little helper function
called second xl1 DG equals pitch and X
next leave Brad equals equals L the old
rat
let's see what it does no I don't use
escape nice control-c Oh should we get
one of those things where my keystrokes
appear on the screen
does that make you guys happy but you're
all like like that I better get
more subscribers because you know I
haven't talked about this no no no no
this is a thing we only talk
about them voltage it's just a serious
twitch but we actually tried our best to
do this oh my god yeah that's great so
we want to do is AB those things to the
suffix tree
six paths shown to the leaves
yeah magic to many of you is this a good
point we don't want that um yeah so this
public efficient ways to write this I'm
not sure if these things are just
because they care about efficiency let's
try to understand here's banana the
sixth path from the root to the leaves
correspond to the suffixes okay so
that's a that's an an that's banana
oh I sort of see
we can just write the stupid thing
quickly I think so buy the stupid thing
I mean like we'll just we'll put these
in a tree structure now we'll start with
a roof node and then these will go back
there and we can increment each one in
the tree structure like going back
that's right that's right
oh man ya know I'd see my I be I be made
fun of by my mom competition program in
people all right
maybe Wikipedia page just bad look let's
really understand what a suffix tree is
Suffolk streams are given types of a
compressed tree while all the suffixes
the given tasks oh okay well that's
interesting so I was looking at it
backwards but because this is supposed
to be looked at backwards it's to be
proper if no string and ass has a suffix
of any other string and ass
there's figure 1 here we go so this is
figure 1
what about mr. Schmidt over no right
eraser I wrote a copywriter a someone's
before his dream you know where he
treasures are sexy yeah I dated and I
want to date with an ad she's man I
didn't go on a date last night so went
on a date in the morning
she lost her ID card on the bus so she
had to like chase a bus in her I don't
know man it was confusing I don't know
what path tracer is but yeah we went on
a date in the morning like what do you
do on a date in the morning
okay
so they said some stuff here too that
was a little bit confusing to me which
like just doesn't make sense that this
is how you're doing inch
oh by the way I remember I thought about
a little more another thing I was
struggling with that log to like why
this is log to the easiest way to think
about it is just like like how yeah how
many symbols do you want to store forget
the negative right if I'm thinking of
two possible values there's two possible
values now it can have one point six
possible values which that gets kind of
interesting but you know if that's the
way things work probabilistically then
there's one point X yeah exactly exactly
and I didn't know I was spending another
night here yeah yeah it's just you know
you know what always kills game man
logistics but also she was mad so
there's that too but like I don't know
it adds adzes there's some nice-looking
ads um she's she's pretty but you know
like command
it's an isotonic drink I learned have
you ever heard this word before guys we
had something about advertising it's
really funny when it's not targeted to
you
exactly no one's ever heard of this
shit's like some weird Malaysia
Singapore okay ask her where we dad
no sweetie I'm not crazy
no I'm not really sure it is chill guys
no worries chill it's chill and I said
you know what we're also drinking some
green tea fresh out of Japan it is it is
hot as balls here gotta be aggressive
what I gotta be yeah no man go yo look
your smoke wheelie UNAM that's fine you
want smoke weed in China that's fine
don't smoke weed in Malaysia don't smoke
weed Dubai does what we do Singapore
don't smoke weed in Indonesia people
crazy don't do that
okay okay no no this makes sense
my PST is a pair were asses of suffix
set and we know what that is and each
thing has a probability oh you forgot to
tell me that it was a real number and
the depths of the suffix n is defined as
the max
like
it does almost seem like I want to flip
these around right this seems the
obvious
bringing drugs here I'm sure there's
plenty of drugs and Malaysia prison
people are out there you know smoking
weed right now in this city and be like
ha ha ha ha ha yeah I'm gonna say
but I don't know I will with that
though Cambodia you can smoke weed
wheeze legal in Cambodia I believe or at
least decriminalized so if you make it a
Cambodia hey if we're guys I promise if
we make it a Cambodia we'll smoke weed I
think is this true
it's illegal but is it like really
illegal Oh although it's illegal
please do not harass cannabis users and
businesses openly sell cannabis products
to the public yeah okay that's that's
that's there that's a good kind of
illegal
so what read it says about - sorry you
guys you're distracting me we have work
to do
get regular they're happy pizzas
hmm
the owner paid attack so his patrons
could smoke weed and his guests as well
as thus Jill some time bars will sell
free roll joints
how do we get the Cambodian guys this
coke everybody smoked weed should do
that they're good I have that product
good weed wait the pharmacies will sell
you any legal prescription drug you'd
like no I don't believe that these
people always ask for shitty drugs like
xanax and valiums
this is not true not like people think
all this is true in Thailand yeah no I
doubt what you think the weeds I thought
the weeds laced man
I'm sure the weeding Cambodia's Chell
about some mad sketch Whedon Berlin once
well it's no laced with anything good
but like the way you know weeds not
gonna be laced is if it's like grows
everywhere in the country
if it's cheap then I got a lace it no do
not do drugs in Cambodia
we what
No
okay this guy had meth and heroin
but the bad news is Cambodia is far away
they looks like all right so I'm here
what if we make it to here and we buy a
boat
what are we in spell everything them in
the cloud well wait but so what if we go
here can we buy a boat in Clandon and
sell our boat across the ocean to kill
her to cambodia cool would that be guys
how cool would that be no no I actually
I know some people here and those are
people in kotha and we could get a boat
here procure a boat and then sail it to
Cambodia no no no but you know what was
swimmable this was swimmable and the
ferry still took forever but like if you
were in the West Valley National Park
you totally could have swam from there
to there
that looks really small discomfort while
okay the other option is we could go
around no I looked it up I might be
wrong about this this is a site I really
like Rome to Rio and the problem is your
choices are to fly or to take bus this
does not sound like a fun bus but do you
really want to be on some eleven in or
bus okay well actually that road doesn't
look that bad I did some of those long
buses and uh they now have GPS world
here
no no this body alright back to work
okay so the only question is like are
these strings reversed or not that's
what I'm not quite understanding
and every suffix set
as I said to be proper if no string Nass
is the suffix of any other string and
that's okay so how do you do that let's
say I have one string and then later I
have this so that's fine because neither
string is the suffix of another drink
but like this string wouldn't be okay
because that's the suffix of that but
then at that rate unless I get identical
things
unless I literally get identical things
I'm not sure how
busses okay all right
III read your chat scroll back safety of
transportation you actually have no idea
how safe bosses are bosses bosses are
safer than trains which is crazy like
like I don't know if I believe any of
these boss things cuz I've been on some
mad sketchy buses right Aaron Aaron Jack
string is the suffix of any other so
oh okay compressed just like collapse as
a couple knows is stupid okay following
or all the suffixes of banana
I guess we actually want to generate all
suffixes to make the tray and that makes
sense we want to add all suffixes of
each of those things to the tree
you can just pick this tall suffix trees
of course it's a tree having more
possible suffixes as notes
they're in all suffixes of individual
text
this is shirtless trip God the air
conditioning starting to kick and they
will push share them I went on a date
with an ad
I hope she never watches my streams
maybe read the source code of suffix
chase
so we can like generate all the suffixes
very fundamental techniques all right
this whole thing's kind of stupid the
set gen thing maybe this isn't what I
wanted
we need an algorithm to construct one
online
no no no she was in Addis and she like
shills for products I mean that's really
the goal of social media
the goal of social media is to turn
people into ads they can code advertise
to their friends okay I understand what
a suffix tree is so here's an N squared
algorithm to construct a suffix J well
that's not gonna work
okay I think it might be time to put
shirt back on air conditioning
[Music]
you know fizzle girl nice
okay
all right let's checking out the other
paper who the other people tell me more
so this is the first paper that
introduced these things
mr. Curtis you asked me the actual stay
of the finite average resource
subsequently this state is used to
estimate the distribution that generates
the next source symbol the estimated
distribution of using arithmetic coding
procedures
I read this stuff yesterday the
concatenation of binary service
laughs starting with zero and going
negative
empty string was a suffix of all strings
so that's like the root note is the
empty string that make sense
statistical behavior of a binary finite
memory tree source can be described by
the means of a suffix set s
each semi infinite sequence there's a
suffix that belongs to us our function
Maps semi-infinite sequences on to their
unique self attacks and s okay this is
started this actually makes a lot of
sense since all suffixes nests have a
length not larger the D so D is that
number of bits thing only the last D
symbols of a 70 but it's infinite
sequence determines up to 80 second for
each suffix there corresponds a
probability together all parameter
formed upon have it okay actually I like
this paper better that's less stupid
like I was marking it but like okay so
those are the parameters your model that
makes sense kind of I mean I guess
there's also parameters of the model in
the suffix tree itself but all right the
tree source yeah this makes sense
actually next symbol probabilities
okay so it seems that such an actually
gonna make sense
forget about coding the first couple
bits now what we'll want to do is we
wanna a class
proper and complete well has to be
complete as well
[Music]
completeness
this suffix is unique since asses proper
completeness I don't know how to get yet
okay I mean I guess I kind of see what
it is right so if both exist
yeah so for the first one the only thing
we can add is just the one because not
not even
so we start out with the set containing
and like it's a draw a cheese danish
thank you for subscribing I'm still
hungry guys I had some some what I have
tonight I am the ring just pretty go Bob
I'm so hungry I'll have to go out off to
get more food so this sets not empty the
set right now has the empty string in it
Suffolk's function function map
semi-infinite sequences on to their
unique suffix s and all suffixes i have
a length not larger than D only the last
D symbols so like we're gonna first
write again and just bad actually
so you can see like okay if you have
empty set that satisfies so you can see
how the empty just the suffix set
containing the empty satisfies proper
and complete
the problem is we have to conspire time
you know espera time in Indonesia you
really knew it was prayer time
because arguable which operating systems
good is stupid
which means I made of this against his
suffix tells us that the parameter for
generating a next binary digit yeah
the actual bla probabilities and
resources with the same suffix that are
said to have the same model but the
parameters can be different okay model
and suffix that are equivalent the set
of all tree models have a memory not
larger than D it's called the model
class CD to specify model in this model
class by a natural code i encode himself
except recursively
interesting
seems complicated maybe the second maybe
it's not all example I love example
pseudo a source dad suffix at
okay
yeah this makes sense
the weighted probability is defined
recursively on the context tree
the way to prove it is it okay so let's
understand these probabilities
how did they get
yes it's not gonna split
until you have one of each
I should have to track the whole thing
at each node I mean that's the naive way
of doing it
each no other corresponds counts a and B
yeah
okay so you can see that two plus two
equals four and one plus two equals
three 1 plus 1 equals 2 2 plus 0 equals
2 ok so that makes sense
mm-hmm to back at this paper
and in GDS
okay
[Music]
let's start out with node
and the nodes gonna have an eight-count
to be count so it's gonna have a one
count and then yeah so how BIG's is
Tregoning at sea
we'll see how big it gets okay this dust
garbage
I get to a certain point with complexity
where I can't really explain it out loud
anymore I can only kind of do it when at
that point and the stuff might be wrong
bogus so I'm better I could
probably explain it you can kind of see
what that's doing right is it right
let's say
now he's nice
okay so that sugar carefully cut the
tree right that number gets to like four
times what I do wrong oh what's that
so that prints the tree
six to nine so now we can use the you
know that tape T estimated it doesn't
like like try criminal so it's one of
those STDs you hear about but you've
never actually heard anybody ever had
that's what I think about when I think
of Katie
hmm
mm-hmm okay that one I shouldn't want to
do about it means it got to the end they
were still notes
[Music]
don't to think about that
yeah
you know I know I know yeah we Yelp and
lasering in Internet
sorry was he back the Russians are
watching that there would just be a one
Oh
so you something that said that p1
mm okay cool
mr. Witter right this whole thing
make sense
you speaking Chinese in my chat
hmm whose work
like
it shouldn't
hm
maybe we do this
zero shouldn't make sense like house and
you're not even created with zeros
I wasn't looking stupid well this was
the node values it's writing the ad yeah
[Music]
okay I mean I just finished okay I guess
I'm terminating to roll
I mean I'm terminating too late that's
better okay we've got some packing ratio
yeah look at that
all right it seems to kind of work
what's up the number best you know the
marketing so much enter page
how is that doing worse than I would it
be that bad
from my perspective I have good
bandwidth I don't know what you guys are
talking about
morning from the East Coast you're up
early
okay so that would mean that these
probabilities are literally just doing
worse than this off
I do wrong
no no you got the right thing I'm just
missing piece that is a suffix true
right
I'm dropping frames I've dropped 8.5% of
the frames that's not so much frames
okay
the node ass is called the pair nodes
and once the zeros there correspond
Kent's bigger than equal to bigger than
me was here
so those are my counts up here see for
any children's yeah so that should
pretty obviously be true
if any look this code right you can
write a test for that but I think so
probability is defined recursively ah
yes but the weighted probability is okay
so this is what we're not doing my
function to fetch is wrong
each node
okay this is kind of confusing but this
is this is the track right so right now
we're rehearsing all the way back and
we're just throwing out the other
probabilities so this is the node
probability so what if we even do this
let's just try
and the why this has P ones and PC
arrows here oh okay it's not totally
shitty anymore surprisingly close to 0.5
okay so let's find the definition of PE
in this code
p zero zero equals one that doesn't make
sense
I'm using the
to each node s NTD we aside a weighted
probability which is defined as ya
the only weird thing I do there is
actually I just want that and say just
call get P again I don't know why it
should be special alright so then this
is just px there oh love it compressed a
little bit I'm not very good
yeah daddy compresses like the same
reason I get more context
we're getting somewhere
she seems like it should be much better
than that I don't understand
kaby bugs I think just good
okay this just proves something's true
about this x NP okay
there's no weighted probability
I understand why
is it true that one - that
the treat of that symmetric
my only question
nice toupee
let's just try some simple examples we
have like one plus point 5/1 bus yeah
it's gonna be that okay that works
that's right
like that might be the problem
changes nothing
I said change nothing
how many ones in zeros
okay so it matches for one over two
not my shirt is worse for tip this
should match it perfectly doesn't and
she does the same as one she's weird
into some bug
because those two should be the same
wasn't supposed to be a morning date
dude I don't know man
girls know the parts of the world or
flaky girls Malaysia like the flakiness
is just different that's that's that's
all we're gonna say about that
that's all I'll talk about about that
topic yeah why was work
[Music]
you
it seemed like when are you checking
which one it will widest we're doing
this a little bit differently
you see what yeah okay so we have three
backs so I think yeah we have like look
up pretty backs or something
so let's get rid of this set check
garbage because they kind of hate it
tinder tinder gold member of Malaysia
let's just copy the same code I mean it
should be using top right I'm gonna need
to make that zero
it's a syntaxerror do not have an except
yeah I got a slightly different number
doing that oh I guess just cuz of the
first
so you're crazy the best let's just try
a little refactor on this
[Music]
that's the same
I don't really understand how those are
different domain what else that's three
notes call get P to compute that so I'm
gonna use it because both though should
be filled in
there's bug
when that should literally be the same
data structure as this just represent a
little bit differently
I'm having an effect
I don't understand this is there gonna
be same go to this okay that's going a
tiny bit off it really doesn't make
sense is maybe this
why is this so far awfulness
called it myself extreme
those two dollars should really just
track the same bed evident and let's
just make something
it's got a stupid mind Swan thing which
is heroes when we go the stats off a
tiny bit
oh okay well that explains that so
number of bits I think in this case has
a different meaning when this says use
one bit it actually means use one bit of
context so what used to be called one
bits actually called zero bits so here
we'll say you know just remember that's
plus one and this could be no that's -
[Music]
okay so that's much more similar you
know that's tracking way more statistics
you can see like this one's the same as
this one so these are the same
yeah seven notes okay that makes that so
you get four there okay that makes sense
I don't know why it's different but all
right that seems correct
so there's stupid recursive things seems
worse - I'm a bit - yes and why is that
so different
leave that there
oh look at that
that's the best we've seen yet this is
next cool the magic of suffix tree okay
so I don't understand why they're doing
that context waiting thing but this
seems to work better if we have context
use it yeah look at that look at that
new record I let's go up to 16 let's add
back in the printing I shouldn't deleted
that hate when I delete stuff that later
want
I'm at an isotonic drink almost I've had
a green tea and the only good thing is
that the compressor kind of works yeah I
know I know I wrote this before get
history course not
tell I have an old get history
Oh guys guys did we just beat dude did
we just be gzip we just be gzip oh oh
hello this crushing it bros
absolutely crushing it bros look at that
look at that
35 bytes of entropy oh yeah go we go
more will be even better
Oh
Bros Bros that was the easiest I
love is gonna be hard I don't even use
their waiting I got it all the way
down to pay all the way down sir no
ma'am now to be fair the only way to
really know whether a compressor has
bugs in it or not is to actually create
the compressed file and then decompress
the file right because if you don't do
that you don't actually know if it has
bugs give me one sec you know what guys
here's what we're gonna do I'm gonna run
out and let's see what foods around here
and then we're gonna come back we're
actually gonna write the arithmetic
coder uhm but yeah we'll just say dat
ratio bro so yes we've written a better
compressor than gzip and how much lines
of Python now know better is an
interesting and well this is all crap we
don't use that so in in 70 lines of
Python we've written a better compressor
than gzip using context tree waiting now
the reason why better is a little bit
subjective is because I'm sure it's much
lower than gzip gzip is not really
designed to be great compression gzip
just wanted to be fast I'm good I lick
the paper just search for context tree
waiting maybe maybe I'll throw that out
I'll put a paper therapy and then you
can you guys can go my github yes it's
just there's a lot of stuff that it Wow
a lot of people have implemented this I
guess I didn't even know Dan just search
for contracts tree waited miss lots of
stuff yeah we'll be back we'll be back
and maybe give me give me give me ten
minutes twenty minutes and then we will
implement the arithmetic code hopefully
oh yeah such good compression such good
compression growth
I seen a bit ma'am it was good it was
good
I had banana roti and it came with curry
but it was weird to dip it in the curry
so I didn't really dip it in the curry I
kind of wanted to get some tosai to dip
in the curry but like I stood there with
the menu open and I kind of just got the
vibe there like who was this guy why the
is he into a restaurant so that was
kind of the vibe I got so I'm gonna wash
my hands cuz I touched money and I ate
food touch my life laughter you know oh
I got this
this was 1:30 Riggins it's kind of a
ripoff usually they're a dollar but the
roti was a great deal
you're gonna write an arithmetic coder
oh yes what's your awake I got some
technically you're into entropy decoder
ah so let's see if we can do this I'm a
little bit tired but we'll enjoy our
best how long they've walking some
monkeys today and I don't mean
Australians and I mean like actual
monkeys sometimes yo you like what
Australians go out to party and drink
while monkeys been let's like pick like
a reasonable number that's like 10 is 10
a reasonable number okay um so the
basics of how arithmetic coding works
broken No
guys is not racist
cuz I'm Australian and a good good good
should we go there should we go we
talked about how according to some new
definitions you're not you can't you
can't be racist against white people I'm
not nuts Hanna believable but you know
now but you have you ever seen if you've
ever seen a group a group of Australians
when they when they come to like one of
these islands to party and then they
were in the hostel that just just just
crazy it's for a while
racism was acceptable only if it's funny
I like that snot funny you can't do it
that was funny
okay so the way that it works
this is even more complicated because
I also thinking about what if you're
wrong there but wait so this is P of X
so that's nice we actually need P of 0
hmm it's not exactly right
that's P of X Q 0 and P of X so what we
actually need is the probability range
that it's in so if X is 1 the range is
going to be from P of X to 1 else
the range is gonna be from 0 point 0 to
P of X now yeah this is this is this is
arithmetic oh yeah
the idea is you just put that range you
scale that range by your current range
and then once things get too small you
have to you like to have to quantize the
probabilities
hmm quantize them anyway
for those of you who missed the date
thing you missed the date thing you got
to watch the earlier stream you don't
get to know if the date was discussed in
detail on the earlier stream
yeah this this is this
hmmm it's cute
so this is just normal arithmetic coding
there's nothing special about this like
I do have I have probabilities I have a
model which it cold
the definition are starting to work well
guys want to see outside
I'd wear my denim jacket this morning
okay
[Music]
approximated by 8-bit precision first
thank god there's patent hate pants all
right so let's round P of x equals P of
x times T six doesn't matter
oh yeah so it cost us two bytes if we
round to the nearest 256
so isn't there a python class calling
for action which I go to Python 3
details for action from fractions and
port fraction loves fraction no math
tool can take oh great it's very
different
so let's just try it a class encoder so
you like just a little bit of
encapsulation here what goes here yet
say code self px and we're gonna do inc
dot code this
[Music]
fraction as in you know I got a
fractions water bottle left a fraction
is green tea left zero fraction which is
a tragedy I do really enjoy those
grantees and I got no fraction of that
left either 100 plus more like zero I
drank it all right what just happened
that was freaky
okay so we want to rescale it to
self-doubt hi - self dot low and what a
multiplier has if that's X is one do
that tells we set the height of that
it's not right
just cold
[Music]
well you don't actually want PDX there
we want P to the zero I know I should
just put this finite precision stuff in
here there's arguments that I shouldn't
whatever those are later on
[Music]
wait a second this isn't right does it
know
don't pass an axe
this isn't even right
hmm see that's what I mean you don't
know if you have a working compressor
till I'll put this back to pee
[Music]
yeah
you can write that right no that's not
right we want to ask us about the first
part of the for action I'm still I'm
still confused about my great thing you
might not even work you know this one
works
the track is really huge numbers
so what do we actually want to say in
south dot h
let's just try this well those numbers
get extremely small
how'd it get negative just crap oh
[Music]
that's better
so yeah once we have bits that we can
remove from both the fractions so I'm
not sure exactly what that means in
practice but that's like what the idea
of arithmetic coding is right like when
your range vision that can be sent to
output range after renormalization the
normalization
no no I mean I think it actually works
he's fracas at infinite precision just
really small
PSEG CDs every time
you understand what I was doing wrong
there
you have an idea
[Music]
okay I think this is actually a :
alright smoke got out arms to t sex
[Music]
can I say dot numerator is that it
I'm probably writing this quite stupidly
[Music]
the date has been extensively discussed
in your division results too large for a
float do that still popping fog
I'll time
I don't even know I'm coming tired
it's really slow
turned into a mourning day because of
aforementioned flakiness this is really
slow I think it's right but it's really
slow okay I'm not using the fraction
plastic fraction
no fraction that
hmm you know what occurs to me that with
finite precision you're sometime gonna
get things on the bounce
I have some bad news that number before
it might be wrong cuz I'm not using X
like I don't know how this is this isn't
actually returning the probability of X
what is it return
what is that returning yes that's not
right cuz we don't use X right like here
we use X and this is correct half a
point is about getting excited bros
that's it you know what twitch doesn't
get to hear about dates anymore
oh jeez if I start to tell you about a
date just to remind me that Ritchie's
don't know about dates anymore this is
some of you guys talk about that and
like all you're using a Mac or can I get
your dot file or what keyboard is that
band not they're not that harsh
okay that's just the previous
so maybe we do this
it breaks it entirely
it's weird there was matching it
just more confident
so you didn't return now
very rare occasions actually it gets the
next one
right
they don't charge you more if you use
more power
oh well no I broke it
I don't understand him I have what I had
before was even close to right but it
was producing right answers which is
weird
yeah I should bring a Bitcoin miner with
me everywhere I go
I draw like 10 kilowatts well I still
think about that if I could pull 10
kilowatts out of power outlet I'm using
just the most worthwhile I mean you get
yourself thrown at a hotels but would
they know you got to be able to take a
lot - he
yeah well so here's our 10 kilowatts
even close to feasible yeah I'm probably
not realistically you're probably on
like a 15 amp circuit to 20 volts in
these parts of the world so you're
getting mingler tool kilowatts powers
like so you're making 20 cents an hour
no it's not so worth it
yeah well not really the better thing to
do would be to figure out how to like
wire into some like streetlights
oh it was right I was just predicting
for the previous body which probably
cheats because it probably uses
we crash more than like normal
Oh your pecans are worthless well
subhanAllah leave damn even tethers are
cheap cheap tether tether press
I guess it's assuming none of the
predictions are wrong
some of them are I don't know
it's annoying when you think you're
close to something and turns out that it
was lies okay so that's one that's the
same as this thing returns when the
answer is born
very close to the same thing we go back
to the pitcher and those obviously
doesn't work
okay so that's giving me the probability
of the next yes so what I'm not tracking
correctly here is like is it the current
symbol or is the next symbol
this is all wrong man
thought we had good before turns
out was all wrong yeah technical
analysis is what you don't use like your
thoughts about the stock you only use
like market fundamentals like Oh what's
a p/e ratio
they all do these people who like pay
money to be in these groups of these
kids who are on Robin Hood and they're
like oh I got day trade of a day trader
bro
I think that's actually better see you
know you just never know that you have
your compressor right until you can
press a file
[Music]
that's more correct
well we're not being gzip anymore guys
these are totally good I think it is
crack now that doesn't make sense okay
it's install the actual blocker okay so
it's all just next symbol probability
[Music]
oh okay that works
okay well now back to the drawing board
how about making things better than
Jesus is now chitty-chitty
maybe now we can use that equation that
doesn't work
okay
now so I feel like we're I feel like
we're like the reason this is wrong as
we're doing it like the wrong way yeah
so that that's of course gonna probably
close to that because the most here's to
us just being thrown away there we go
the other way it's more correct right
you see what I mean by the other way
okay we're back again worse than Jesus
don't don't we celebrated twirly guys we
celebrated too early no just great
tragic now we're gonna make the whole
compressor actually work maybe not
tonight but at some point oh okay that's
not right but what we really want to do
yeah so we're recursing back through
things and we want that one to have that
point five wait
not the current one
so I could return the whole list
and then compute it afterwards or is
there just a cute recursive way to do
this
mr. Schine West
we're constructing a stupid list every
time
yeah
so that's effectively that that should
give me like nineties yeah
now we want to do is make the first one
weighed the highest so maybe just for
accent now we're at equals out
so to be clear the money alone is the
one that goes yeah so we'll get rid of
that one put them around rat equals
super 500 plus 0.5 times Oh
all right well we're not back to beating
gzip but at least we're gonna be
ambitious and we're gonna write the
encoder tragedy but we're actually doing
the waiting maybe we can even make this
big oh come on Bee Gees up again no I
can't be Jesus Jim juice you're the good
guys
Jesus Jesus super talented you know oh
just go Yosh
going a huge number notes and doesn't
even look better garbage
thank you for the bids Dortmund I always
appreciated money you know in this world
we've all money
trust me Malaysia money it's beautiful
beautiful morning
alright I think we have to settle for
just fixing it
no no they already got my stream I'll
think about the encoder event yeah so
okay okay
we prematurely celebrated in the
previous stream but we really did get
things down from like what I ain't wrote
in the reasoning what they wire I just
dropped telling for BT that Vizag
Oh
that's it does we got Mavis gym tomorrow
she write the ACMA decoder entire dogs
bedtime late that was later last no no
I'm tired no no that was a lie that was
a lie I messed up the calculation that
that was that was assuming none of my
prediction wrong that's the hypothetical
maximum with the levels of precision we
had we've actually only gotten to here
now we weren't quite predicting the past
we were just saying none of my
predictions would be wrong the tree was
the choosing cutting their own thing
it's encoding the right thing now I
think I don't know crystally wrong the
only way don't know for sure is well
write an arithmetic encoder and will
generate the file and then we'll
decompress it and a little difficulty
make sure they're the same stinking okay
at least now we have a good
well when you talk about domain-specific
compressions is why you also talk about
the length of the coat and sure I mean
everything you can think of is probably
not everything like I guess like cheese
it's not but like PNG PNG is just Jesus
all these 77 zits deflate it deflate the
same thing as gzip I don't even know
yeah so somebody it's not Jeezy mpg I
believe PNG actually uses a Huffman code
and not an arithmetic code and this has
been talked about before but one of them
because Huffman codes are much easier to
write he's gonna write this arithmetic
coder
hmm
I didn't try to simulate infinite
precision
hmm oh gee this might be okay what if I
just send one bit at a time to the
output in a way it's slower but
we want to try to use for action again
surely p0
I think it matters but
the only thing about p0 is not as I said
make some sounds but
yeah I mean this is fundamentally what
you want to do whether use fraction
library or not you see like so what
that's doing I'm tracking a low and a
high and like you're in the yellow arrow
doing that yellow arrow you're in that
yellow area but I think I can say if
Danny output zero
[Applause]
and I want the same bug that ever the
last time I wrote this
I'm sure which was you actually had X
really was one let me move that up
- there and I've actually was heroes and
I think reaction was I won - here
it's amazing any code I write it works
so maybe I'm a terrible programmer like
I don't know people like think this
stuff out more well they just kind of
try things until it works
where people like sit down with like
paper and try to figure things out maybe
I should do that instead of trying to
keep this in my head that sounds boring
yeah so then whenever we can remove
precision from these fractions we want
to show it that means
a fraction sucks losing as a way to
think about things
[Music]
well the problem really is this
multiplication
let's find a reason to fractionate right
here we'll say self dot d x equal 36
here we want to do less equals t 0 but
we have to rescale these to the old so
that's the whole problem I wouldn't have
to scale them and just be trivial
oh god I shouldn't do this and see what
you have to deal with like the fact the
name
so this was easier
like it's so easy in theory but then you
have to deal with finite precision
can I keep the denominator something
reasonable when you multiply fractions
you multiply the numerators and multiply
denominators right good I don't know is
that you multiply fractions does that
make sense
yeah you multiply fractions you multiply
the numerators new month with
denominators you subtract fractions okay
so you're self-taught range range
numerator equals subsidy myself that age
range denominator which equals D
okay then we want to want to rescale p0
to be in that range so we want to
multiply p0 times the range numerator
multiplied the denominator times the
range to nominate it so right okay the
denominators are gonna get huge fast but
that's
getting negative numbers again
I hate negative numbers
okay so we take p0 put into the range we
can just multiply it by the range
numerator three fourths so there are
five nine eighty three fourths
this is the same thing as 9 over 16
okay so now if X is zero then we want to
set too high
that's okay
and think
yeah guys I'm tired real asleep we'll do
this more tomorrow they'll make it work
when guys are watching my live bat and
try to make it work yeah later